<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tracy Real Estate Video Blog with Paul Lopez</title>
    <description>Our mission at Team Paul Lopez is to be your best resource for Tracy real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Team Paul Lopez, your professional Tracy Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 10:12:37 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 10:12:37 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Achieve Your 2020 Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/BHJS1YLEuKs?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2020! Now is a great time to take a moment and think about the events that will happen this year. Today I want to share three key tips that will make this a more successful, productive, and prosperous year for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first thing you should do is take a look at the next 11 months before you.&lt;/strong&gt; Remember that the end of the year is filled with holidays and events. Plan out the year according to the calendar and the events that will happen this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next, take a closer look at the goals you want to achieve in 2020.&lt;/strong&gt; Find out what brings meaning to the activities that you do every day like showing up to your job and prospecting, and how it all brings meaning to your purpose. When you look at your purpose, how does that relate to the goals you want to achieve in 2020? When it comes time to accomplish your goals, I encourage you to be truly present in your daily work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Find out what brings meaning to the activities that you do every day.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-achieve-your-2020-goals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Find out what brings meaning to the activities that you do every day.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, if you know that you’re going to buy, sell, or invest in 2020, the time to start planning is now.&lt;/strong&gt; Once again, keep the end in mind and the various steps that it will take to get you there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to talk with me to talk about your goals for 2020, I’m happy to offer a free, no-obligation sit down. Just give me a call or send an email so we can get something set up. If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 13:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-achieve-your-2020-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-achieve-your-2020-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Simple Things in Life Give Us the Most Profound Blessings</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/1x3KEm1NX9c?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the simple things in life that often turn out to be the most profound blessings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I was thinking about a good friend of mine, and one of the things we have in common is we both enjoy 80s music. Whenever we’re together and 80s music comes on, a great sense of joy fills the air. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have another friend I don’t get to see very often, but whenever I do see them, our conversations are so deep and meaningful. There is so much wisdom shared about our lives, our families, and everything we have in common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I love helping families with their real estate needs.%20http://localhost:4000/the-simple-things-in-life-give-us-the-most-profound-blessings.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I love helping families with their real estate needs.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dad is my greatest friend, and regardless of where I am in life, he has an extra special way of picking me up and encouraging me that the sky is the limit and there are endless opportunities for what I can do with my life. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is, &lt;strong&gt;there are so many great opportunities around us that are so simple,&lt;/strong&gt; and when we take a moment to look at the space around us and the wonderful things in our life, you can feel a sense of profound gratitude fill your day and give you a boost of energy. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love helping families with their real estate needs. Whether it’s buying, selling, or renting a home, I love to connect with my clients and finding ways that they can achieve their goals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to connect with you and be of service any way I can, so reach out to me anytime if you have any real estate needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-simple-things-in-life-give-us-the-most-profound-blessings.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-simple-things-in-life-give-us-the-most-profound-blessings.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Start Preparing for 2020 Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/EdVS9Srn5Q8?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three months from now, 2019 will be over and we’ll be into 2020. That makes right now the perfect time to start thinking about your goals for the new year and finish up some of your goals from 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re doing any financial planning and thinking about refinancing or buying a home, you should know that interest rates are still incredibly low right now.&lt;/strong&gt; A 30-year fixed-rate mortgage can be had for around 3.5% interest, while 15-year terms can be had for around 3%. Now is a great time to check up on your current mortgage to see if you can save from these changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanksgiving and Christmas are coming up. Have you budgeted for these holidays? &lt;strong&gt;If not, it’s a good idea to do so now.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Now is a great time to check up on your current mortgage.%20http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-start-preparing-for-2020-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Now is a great time to check up on your current mortgage.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, is your home ready to withstand the winter months? Check your exterior to make sure there are no cracks, and make sure your gutters are clean and in proper working order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a plan to buy or sell a home in 2020, don’t hesitate to reach out to me and give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to offer my expertise to hopefully prepare you. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 10:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-start-preparing-for-2020-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-start-preparing-for-2020-now.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Steps Will Help You Organize Your Finances</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HVBlYG8xQok?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re buying your very first home, selling your current home and buying another one, or are considering real estate as an investment strategy, your first order of business will be to organize your finances. There are three main steps you must take to do so. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, &lt;strong&gt;check your credit report.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether you have perfect credit or your credit score needs work, you should take advantage of the many resources available to consumers such as yourself. Checking your credit doesn’t affect your credit score, but it’s a great place to start because you can find out exactly what’s being reported. And if you discover any errors, you have plenty of time to correct them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;consider where your down payment and closing costs are coming from&lt;/strong&gt; (and remember that these are two separate things). You’ll want to know how much funds you’ll have to work with and where you’ll access these funds. Perhaps they’ll come from a savings account, or perhaps from a 401(k) or retirement plan. In the latter case, you’ll want to talk to your funds advisor sooner rather than later so you can learn the rules for using that money for your home purchase. The same applies if you’ve gone through a life-changing event (e.g., getting divorced or receiving an inheritance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Whether you have perfect credit or your credit score needs work, you should take advantage of the many resources available to consumers such as yourself.%20http://localhost:4000/these-3-steps-will-help-you-organize-your-finances.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Whether you have perfect credit or your credit score needs work, you should take advantage of the many resources available to consumers such as yourself.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to organizing your finances, &lt;strong&gt;make sure you meet with an experienced mortgage professional&lt;/strong&gt;—one who’ll sit down with you and take the time to fully understand your financial situation and your prospective home purchase. They’ll outline how much your down payment, closing costs, and monthly mortgage payments will be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buying a home is an emotionally charged transaction, and there are many steps you’ll go through to complete the transaction. With the right team behind you, though, this transaction can be seamless and quite enjoyable. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know more about organizing your finances or you have any other real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 11:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/these-3-steps-will-help-you-organize-your-finances.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/these-3-steps-will-help-you-organize-your-finances.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Help You Through Your Home Sale</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Z-80Rvmpbj4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you considering selling your home and starting to realize what an emotional roller coaster it can be? You have to choose your broker, prepare your home for sale, and identify your new home all while life is still happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where your real estate broker can bring calmness and clarity to an event that can be very stressful if not dealt with precisely. &lt;strong&gt;Here are several key areas that you should focus on as a home seller to create a clear home-selling strategy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Pricing your home.&lt;/strong&gt; When it comes to pricing your home, you certainly don’t want to go too high. Buyers and consumers can obtain all the information they need to find out what your home is actually worth. You won’t trick them by overpricing. When you bring all the data and info together, you can come up with a great price. It’s also important to know how much money you’re going to walk away with in your pocket at the end of the day. After you’ve determined pricing and your net cash and marketing plan, it’s time to get your home on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Make sure your home can be seen at a moment’s notice.%20http://localhost:4000/3-tips-to-help-you-through-your-home-sale.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Make sure your home can be seen at a moment’s notice.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Showing availability.&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure your home can be seen at a moment’s notice. Buyers looking at your home could be from out of the area without the time to schedule a perfect appointment, but you should do everything you can to accommodate them. It can be stressful to have your home perfect all the time, but make it as a viewable as possible to help out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Hire a real estate broker you trust.&lt;/strong&gt; This person should understand your expectations and be a team leader. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to talk to you about how we can bring this kind of calmness and clarity to a stressful transaction like this. If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-tips-to-help-you-through-your-home-sale.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/3-tips-to-help-you-through-your-home-sale.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breaking These Rules Will Ruin Your Mortgage</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4wpSZ1zb0Xk?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes time for your mortgage lender to submit your documentation to the underwriting department, it can take anywhere from three to four weeks for them to come up with a decision. When you’re going through this process, the lender may come back to you and ask for additional documentation or to resubmit prior documents. Keep in mind that you’re asking the bank to lend you a large amount of money and they want to get as much documentation as they need to process the loan, so please be patient and keep a good attitude through it all as this can be a lengthy process. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve taken a lot of time to research and carefully select the property you want to call home or a property that you want to invest in.&lt;/strong&gt; Whatever the case may be, you want to make sure you take these four rules into account so your loan process goes as smooth as possible:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Don’t change employment.&lt;/strong&gt; There are certain circumstances that come up where you feel that it’s time to leave your job and look for a new one. However, when your loan is in the underwriting process for the purchase of a home, stay exactly where you are financially until after closing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Large purchases could result in the denial of your loan.%20http://localhost:4000/breaking-these-rules-will-ruin-your-mortgage.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Large purchases could result in the denial of your loan.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Avoid using your credit cards as much as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; At the same time, don’t close any cards or open up any new lines of credit. It’s not a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Avoid making any large purchases.&lt;/strong&gt; It can be tempting to buy a new car or new furniture if you need it, but it should be avoided until after the loan is funded. These purchases could result in the denial of your loan or the end of your transaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Don’t open, close, or transfer bank accounts.&lt;/strong&gt; Your loan officer has already taken your current financial picture into consideration, so it’s wise to keep it exactly where it is through the underwriting process. This underwriting time frame can be difficult to deal with, but in the end, it’s a very rewarding experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me about the mortgage process or about real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 13:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/breaking-these-rules-will-ruin-your-mortgage.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/breaking-these-rules-will-ruin-your-mortgage.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Strategy That Will Find the Right Home for You and Your Family</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_tavUiQEj6U?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a homebuyer, what steps must you take to ensure you find the right home for you and your family?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, choose an experienced Real Estate Broker to work with.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s important to start with this task because a good Real Estate Broker will help formulate your strategy. When it comes to buying a home, no two scenarios are exactly alike, which means there’s no one-size-fits-all solution. Your Real Estate Broker will guide you through the process, remind you of your original objectives, and make sure you meet them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to selecting a home to purchase, I recommend thinking of it as a process of elimination. You don’t want to miss out on anything available, so begin by identifying which cities you want to live in. This will narrow down to several different factors, including your buying power, budget, and the location of these cities with respect to your daily commute. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you’ve settled on one city, narrow your focus further to the neighborhoods of that city. This will be determined by factors such as school districts, shopping centers, your work commute, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once you’ve decided on the neighborhoods you’d like to live in, it’s time to amp up your research, especially online.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll want to talk to different people who live in these neighborhoods to really get a sense of whether they’re ideal for your family. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I’ve employed this strategy for close to 20 years, and it’s one of the most effective ways to find a home that meets the needs of your family.%20http://localhost:4000/the-strategy-that-will-find-the-right-home-for-you-and-your-family.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I’ve employed this strategy for close to 20 years, and it’s one of the most effective ways to find a home that meets the needs of your family.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’ve decided on a single neighborhood, it’s time to visit open houses in the area. Open houses are a great way to view homes—you can spend as much time as you want looking around inside and considering all the amenities the home has to offer. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, you should be communicating with your Real Estate Broker the information you’ve discovered and how it applies to your situation. They can get different estimates for you and advise you on any neighborhood information that’s not public information. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you talk to your Real Estate Broker, schedule in-person visits to the homes on your short list. You started big, but now you’ve narrowed your search all the way down to the homes you may want to make an offer on. It’s during this point your Realtor should remind you of your original objectives and make sure the homes you see in person will meet your needs. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ve employed this strategy for close to 20 years, and it’s one of the most effective ways to find a home that meets the needs of your family.&lt;/strong&gt;  After all is said and done, you and your Real Estate Broker will write a strong offer and, if it’s accepted, begin closing on your new home. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to talk more about the best home buying strategy for you or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 11:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-strategy-that-will-find-the-right-home-for-you-and-your-family.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-strategy-that-will-find-the-right-home-for-you-and-your-family.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Be Writing Down Your Goals</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2451mK6HNGQ?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking about buying your very first home, but you don’t quite know how it’s going to happen? Well, &lt;strong&gt;today I want to encourage you to make homeownership a goal and write it down.&lt;/strong&gt; Then review your goal as often as you possibly can to keep it fresh in your mind. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not too long ago, I had a specific goal about buying a piece of property. I wrote it down, looked at it daily, and over time, my subconscious went to work for me and I took the necessary steps to make that goal happen. &lt;strong&gt;I reduced some debt, got rid of a few other things, and I was able to get the property that was important to me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I want you to write your goals down and look at them every day.%20http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-be-writing-down-your-goals.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I want you to write your goals down and look at them every day.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started with a goal. What are your personal and professional goals? I want you to write them down and look at them every day. One day, when your goals have been accomplished, you’ll be grateful that you took the step to write them down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for me in the meantime about real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 21:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-be-writing-down-your-goals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-be-writing-down-your-goals.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Hire the Right Agent for Your Transaction</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5XGe83MqVWY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about making a move in real estate—whether it be to buy, sell, or rent a property—choosing the right agent is an invaluable aspect of your future success. Today I’ll discuss three factors to consider in an agent to help you make sure you’re hiring the very best professional help for your next transaction:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Consider their experience.&lt;/strong&gt; There are many steps in the real estate process, and some potential issues are predictable while others are not. Agents with experience in these matters will help get you through the process with as little stress as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Consider their communication skills.&lt;/strong&gt; The best agent to hire is one who will do their best to proactively communicate with you to keep you up to date on the transaction. This may occur via phone, email, or text—whichever works best to keep them in consistent contact with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Do you have a connection with them?&lt;/strong&gt; Does your agent really understand you and your family’s needs? Do they truly get why it’s important for you to succeed in your transaction? A great agent will take the time to connect with you and make sure they’re working in your best interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to discuss how our team can help you meet your real estate goals, feel free to reach out to us. I’d love to have the opportunity to talk to you.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 11:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-hire-the-right-agent-for-your-transaction.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-hire-the-right-agent-for-your-transaction.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Choose a Loan Officer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xcegi86_FFM?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our current market conditions offer a unique set of circumstances. For one thing, interest rates are still at historic lows. This makes buying a home quite affordable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you can take advantage of these circumstances, however, you’ll need to choose a loan officer to work with. So, should you choose a local professional, or will you work with a big bank? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s actually no one-size-fits-all answer. For some, working with a big bank (like Wells Fargo, Bank of America, or Capital One, etc.) may be the right way to go. For others, working with an independent loan officer may be best. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where I come in. My team and I have the tools, knowledge, and experience to help you determine which option is best for your personal opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You should only trust true experts to help you navigate the financial side of a real estate deal.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-choose-a-loan-officer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You should only trust true experts to help you navigate the financial side of a real estate deal.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of which route you go, though, the loan officer you work with must be able to fulfill a few specific criteria:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They must be strong communicators.&lt;/strong&gt; The person, or team, you choose to work with should be willing and able to stay in touch with you throughout the process. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They must be a team player.&lt;/strong&gt; There are many different professionals involved in the real estate process. Your loan officer must be willing to work and communicate with all of them to keep your deal moving smoothly. &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They must be skilled and resourceful.&lt;/strong&gt; It goes without saying that you should only trust true experts to help you navigate the financial side of a real estate deal. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me or my team a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 23:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-choose-a-loan-officer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-choose-a-loan-officer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
