<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Tracy Real Estate Podcast with Paul Lopez</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Team Paul Lopez - your professional Tracy Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Paul Lopez</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-02-03 10:12:37 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Paul Lopez</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/twitter.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>Paul@TeamLopez.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Paul Lopez</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/uploads/twitter.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Tracy Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Team Paul Lopez - your professional Tracy Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Achieve Your 2020 Goals</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-achieve-your-2020-goals.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2020-01-17 13:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Welcome to 2020! Now is a great time to take a moment and think about the events that will happen this year. Today I want to share three key tips that will make this a more successful, productive, and prosperous year for you.

The first thing you should do is take a look at the next 11 months before you. Remember that the end of the year is filled with holidays and events. Plan out the year according to the calendar and the events that will happen this year.

Next, take a closer look at the goals you want to achieve in 2020. Find out what brings meaning to the activities that you do every day like showing up to your job and prospecting, and how it all brings meaning to your purpose. When you look at your purpose, how does that relate to the goals you want to achieve in 2020? When it comes time to accomplish your goals, I encourage you to be truly present in your daily work.

“Find out what brings meaning to the activities that you do every day.”

Finally, if you know that you’re going to buy, sell, or invest in 2020, the time to start planning is now. Once again, keep the end in mind and the various steps that it will take to get you there.

If you want to talk with me to talk about your goals for 2020, I’m happy to offer a free, no-obligation sit down. Just give me a call or send an email so we can get something set up. If you have any other questions, don’t hesitate to reach out. I look forward to hearing from you.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>I have three tips to share today that will help you accomplish more in 2020.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>I have three tips to share today that will help you accomplish more in 2020.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Simple Things in Life Give Us the Most Profound Blessings</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-simple-things-in-life-give-us-the-most-profound-blessings.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-17 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/The+Simple+Things+in+Life+Give+Us+the+Most+Profound+Blessings.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s the simple things in life that often turn out to be the most profound blessings. 

Recently, I was thinking about a good friend of mine, and one of the things we have in common is we both enjoy 80s music. Whenever we’re together and 80s music comes on, a great sense of joy fills the air. 

I have another friend I don’t get to see very often, but whenever I do see them, our conversations are so deep and meaningful. There is so much wisdom shared about our lives, our families, and everything we have in common.

“I love helping families with their real estate needs.”

My dad is my greatest friend, and regardless of where I am in life, he has an extra special way of picking me up and encouraging me that the sky is the limit and there are endless opportunities for what I can do with my life. 

The point is, there are so many great opportunities around us that are so simple, and when we take a moment to look at the space around us and the wonderful things in our life, you can feel a sense of profound gratitude fill your day and give you a boost of energy. 

I love helping families with their real estate needs. Whether it’s buying, selling, or renting a home, I love to connect with my clients and finding ways that they can achieve their goals. 

I’d love to connect with you and be of service any way I can, so reach out to me anytime if you have any real estate needs.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/The+Simple+Things+in+Life+Give+Us+the+Most+Profound+Blessings.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/The+Simple+Things+in+Life+Give+Us+the+Most+Profound+Blessings.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It’s important that we appreciate the simple things in life. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It’s important that we appreciate the simple things in life. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Start Preparing for 2020 Now</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-start-preparing-for-2020-now.html</link>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-10-17 10:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Why+You+Should+Start+Preparing+for+2020+Now.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Three months from now, 2019 will be over and we’ll be into 2020. That makes right now the perfect time to start thinking about your goals for the new year and finish up some of your goals from 2019.

If you’re doing any financial planning and thinking about refinancing or buying a home, you should know that interest rates are still incredibly low right now. A 30-year fixed-rate mortgage can be had for around 3.5% interest, while 15-year terms can be had for around 3%. Now is a great time to check up on your current mortgage to see if you can save from these changes.

Thanksgiving and Christmas are coming up. Have you budgeted for these holidays? If not, it’s a good idea to do so now.

“Now is a great time to check up on your current mortgage.”

Finally, is your home ready to withstand the winter months? Check your exterior to make sure there are no cracks, and make sure your gutters are clean and in proper working order.

If you have a plan to buy or sell a home in 2020, don’t hesitate to reach out to me and give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to offer my expertise to hopefully prepare you. I look forward to hearing from you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Why+You+Should+Start+Preparing+for+2020+Now.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Why+You+Should+Start+Preparing+for+2020+Now.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Have you started planning for 2020 yet? If not, here’s some advice to help get you started on the right foot.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Have you started planning for 2020 yet? If not, here’s some advice to help get you started on the right foot.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>These 3 Steps Will Help You Organize Your Finances</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/these-3-steps-will-help-you-organize-your-finances.html</link>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-30 11:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/These+3+Steps+Will+Help+You+Organize+Your+Finances.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Whether you’re buying your very first home, selling your current home and buying another one, or are considering real estate as an investment strategy, your first order of business will be to organize your finances. There are three main steps you must take to do so. 

First, check your credit report. Whether you have perfect credit or your credit score needs work, you should take advantage of the many resources available to consumers such as yourself. Checking your credit doesn’t affect your credit score, but it’s a great place to start because you can find out exactly what’s being reported. And if you discover any errors, you have plenty of time to correct them. 

Second, consider where your down payment and closing costs are coming from (and remember that these are two separate things). You’ll want to know how much funds you’ll have to work with and where you’ll access these funds. Perhaps they’ll come from a savings account, or perhaps from a 401(k) or retirement plan. In the latter case, you’ll want to talk to your funds advisor sooner rather than later so you can learn the rules for using that money for your home purchase. The same applies if you’ve gone through a life-changing event (e.g., getting divorced or receiving an inheritance).

“Whether you have perfect credit or your credit score needs work, you should take advantage of the many resources available to consumers such as yourself.”

When it comes to organizing your finances, make sure you meet with an experienced mortgage professional—one who’ll sit down with you and take the time to fully understand your financial situation and your prospective home purchase. They’ll outline how much your down payment, closing costs, and monthly mortgage payments will be. 

Buying a home is an emotionally charged transaction, and there are many steps you’ll go through to complete the transaction. With the right team behind you, though, this transaction can be seamless and quite enjoyable. 

If you’d like to know more about organizing your finances or you have any other real estate questions, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.  
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/These+3+Steps+Will+Help+You+Organize+Your+Finances.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/These+3+Steps+Will+Help+You+Organize+Your+Finances.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you need to organize your finances, there are three main steps you must take.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you need to organize your finances, there are three main steps you must take.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips to Help You Through Your Home Sale</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-tips-to-help-you-through-your-home-sale.html</link>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-17 14:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/3+Tips+to+Help+You+Through+Your+Home+Sale.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you considering selling your home and starting to realize what an emotional roller coaster it can be? You have to choose your broker, prepare your home for sale, and identify your new home all while life is still happening.

This is where your real estate broker can bring calmness and clarity to an event that can be very stressful if not dealt with precisely. Here are several key areas that you should focus on as a home seller to create a clear home-selling strategy:

1. Pricing your home. When it comes to pricing your home, you certainly don’t want to go too high. Buyers and consumers can obtain all the information they need to find out what your home is actually worth. You won’t trick them by overpricing. When you bring all the data and info together, you can come up with a great price. It’s also important to know how much money you’re going to walk away with in your pocket at the end of the day. After you’ve determined pricing and your net cash and marketing plan, it’s time to get your home on the market.

“Make sure your home can be seen at a moment’s notice.”

2. Showing availability. Make sure your home can be seen at a moment’s notice. Buyers looking at your home could be from out of the area without the time to schedule a perfect appointment, but you should do everything you can to accommodate them. It can be stressful to have your home perfect all the time, but make it as a viewable as possible to help out.

3. Hire a real estate broker you trust. This person should understand your expectations and be a team leader. 

I’d love to talk to you about how we can bring this kind of calmness and clarity to a stressful transaction like this. If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon. 

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/3+Tips+to+Help+You+Through+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/3+Tips+to+Help+You+Through+Your+Home+Sale.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If a home sale is in your future, I’ve got a few helpful tips for you today to make the process simpler and smoother.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If a home sale is in your future, I’ve got a few helpful tips for you today to make the process simpler and smoother.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Breaking These Rules Will Ruin Your Mortgage</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/breaking-these-rules-will-ruin-your-mortgage.html</link>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-06 13:28:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Breaking+These+Rules+Will+Ruin+Your+Mortgage.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When it comes time for your mortgage lender to submit your documentation to the underwriting department, it can take anywhere from three to four weeks for them to come up with a decision. When you’re going through this process, the lender may come back to you and ask for additional documentation or to resubmit prior documents. Keep in mind that you’re asking the bank to lend you a large amount of money and they want to get as much documentation as they need to process the loan, so please be patient and keep a good attitude through it all as this can be a lengthy process. 

You’ve taken a lot of time to research and carefully select the property you want to call home or a property that you want to invest in. Whatever the case may be, you want to make sure you take these four rules into account so your loan process goes as smooth as possible:

1. Don’t change employment. There are certain circumstances that come up where you feel that it’s time to leave your job and look for a new one. However, when your loan is in the underwriting process for the purchase of a home, stay exactly where you are financially until after closing.

“Large purchases could result in the denial of your loan.”

2. Avoid using your credit cards as much as possible. At the same time, don’t close any cards or open up any new lines of credit. It’s not a good idea.

3. Avoid making any large purchases. It can be tempting to buy a new car or new furniture if you need it, but it should be avoided until after the loan is funded. These purchases could result in the denial of your loan or the end of your transaction.

4. Don’t open, close, or transfer bank accounts. Your loan officer has already taken your current financial picture into consideration, so it’s wise to keep it exactly where it is through the underwriting process. This underwriting time frame can be difficult to deal with, but in the end, it’s a very rewarding experience.

If you have any questions for me about the mortgage process or about real estate in general, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Breaking+These+Rules+Will+Ruin+Your+Mortgage.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Breaking+These+Rules+Will+Ruin+Your+Mortgage.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If a mortgage is in your future, I have some tips to share today that could help you get approved.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If a mortgage is in your future, I have some tips to share today that could help you get approved.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Strategy That Will Find the Right Home for You and Your Family</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-strategy-that-will-find-the-right-home-for-you-and-your-family.html</link>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-20 11:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/The+Strategy+That+Will+Find+the+Right+Home+for+You+and+Your+Family+(2).mp4</guid>
        <description>

As a homebuyer, what steps must you take to ensure you find the right home for you and your family?

First, choose an experienced Real Estate Broker to work with. It’s important to start with this task because a good Real Estate Broker will help formulate your strategy. When it comes to buying a home, no two scenarios are exactly alike, which means there’s no one-size-fits-all solution. Your Real Estate Broker will guide you through the process, remind you of your original objectives, and make sure you meet them. 

When it comes to selecting a home to purchase, I recommend thinking of it as a process of elimination. You don’t want to miss out on anything available, so begin by identifying which cities you want to live in. This will narrow down to several different factors, including your buying power, budget, and the location of these cities with respect to your daily commute. 

After you’ve settled on one city, narrow your focus further to the neighborhoods of that city. This will be determined by factors such as school districts, shopping centers, your work commute, etc. 

Once you’ve decided on the neighborhoods you’d like to live in, it’s time to amp up your research, especially online. You’ll want to talk to different people who live in these neighborhoods to really get a sense of whether they’re ideal for your family. 

“I’ve employed this strategy for close to 20 years, and it’s one of the most effective ways to find a home that meets the needs of your family.”

When you’ve decided on a single neighborhood, it’s time to visit open houses in the area. Open houses are a great way to view homes—you can spend as much time as you want looking around inside and considering all the amenities the home has to offer. 

Meanwhile, you should be communicating with your Real Estate Broker the information you’ve discovered and how it applies to your situation. They can get different estimates for you and advise you on any neighborhood information that’s not public information. 

After you talk to your Real Estate Broker, schedule in-person visits to the homes on your short list. You started big, but now you’ve narrowed your search all the way down to the homes you may want to make an offer on. It’s during this point your Realtor should remind you of your original objectives and make sure the homes you see in person will meet your needs. 

I’ve employed this strategy for close to 20 years, and it’s one of the most effective ways to find a home that meets the needs of your family.  After all is said and done, you and your Real Estate Broker will write a strong offer and, if it’s accepted, begin closing on your new home. 

If you’d like to talk more about the best home buying strategy for you or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/The+Strategy+That+Will+Find+the+Right+Home+for+You+and+Your+Family+(2).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/The+Strategy+That+Will+Find+the+Right+Home+for+You+and+Your+Family+(2).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re unsure where to start as a homebuyer, this strategy will help you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re unsure where to start as a homebuyer, this strategy will help you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why You Should Be Writing Down Your Goals</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/why-you-should-be-writing-down-your-goals.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-04 21:42:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Why+You+Should+Be+Writing+Down+Your+Goals.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Are you thinking about buying your very first home, but you don’t quite know how it’s going to happen? Well, today I want to encourage you to make homeownership a goal and write it down. Then review your goal as often as you possibly can to keep it fresh in your mind. 

Not too long ago, I had a specific goal about buying a piece of property. I wrote it down, looked at it daily, and over time, my subconscious went to work for me and I took the necessary steps to make that goal happen. I reduced some debt, got rid of a few other things, and I was able to get the property that was important to me.

“I want you to write your goals down and look at them every day.”

It all started with a goal. What are your personal and professional goals? I want you to write them down and look at them every day. One day, when your goals have been accomplished, you’ll be grateful that you took the step to write them down.

If you have any questions for me in the meantime about real estate, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Why+You+Should+Be+Writing+Down+Your+Goals.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Why+You+Should+Be+Writing+Down+Your+Goals.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It may seem far fetched, but writing down your goals on paper will increase your odds of achieving them. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It may seem far fetched, but writing down your goals on paper will increase your odds of achieving them. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Hire the Right Agent for Your Transaction</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-hire-the-right-agent-for-your-transaction.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-19 11:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+to+Hire+the+Right+Agent+for+Your+Transaction.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about making a move in real estate—whether it be to buy, sell, or rent a property—choosing the right agent is an invaluable aspect of your future success. Today I’ll discuss three factors to consider in an agent to help you make sure you’re hiring the very best professional help for your next transaction:

1. Consider their experience. There are many steps in the real estate process, and some potential issues are predictable while others are not. Agents with experience in these matters will help get you through the process with as little stress as possible.

2. Consider their communication skills. The best agent to hire is one who will do their best to proactively communicate with you to keep you up to date on the transaction. This may occur via phone, email, or text—whichever works best to keep them in consistent contact with you.

3. Do you have a connection with them? Does your agent really understand you and your family’s needs? Do they truly get why it’s important for you to succeed in your transaction? A great agent will take the time to connect with you and make sure they’re working in your best interests.

If you’d like to discuss how our team can help you meet your real estate goals, feel free to reach out to us. I’d love to have the opportunity to talk to you. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+to+Hire+the+Right+Agent+for+Your+Transaction.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+to+Hire+the+Right+Agent+for+Your+Transaction.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>For home sellers and buyers, the agent you choose is a very important factor in your success.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>For home sellers and buyers, the agent you choose is a very important factor in your success.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Choose a Loan Officer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-choose-a-loan-officer.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-09 23:54:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/How+to+Choose+a+Loan+Officer+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our current market conditions offer a unique set of circumstances. For one thing, interest rates are still at historic lows. This makes buying a home quite affordable.

Before you can take advantage of these circumstances, however, you’ll need to choose a loan officer to work with. So, should you choose a local professional, or will you work with a big bank? 

There’s actually no one-size-fits-all answer. For some, working with a big bank (like Wells Fargo, Bank of America, or Capital One, etc.) may be the right way to go. For others, working with an independent loan officer may be best. 

This is where I come in. My team and I have the tools, knowledge, and experience to help you determine which option is best for your personal opportunity. 

“You should only trust true experts to help you navigate the financial side of a real estate deal.”

Regardless of which route you go, though, the loan officer you work with must be able to fulfill a few specific criteria:


  They must be strong communicators. The person, or team, you choose to work with should be willing and able to stay in touch with you throughout the process. 
  They must be a team player. There are many different professionals involved in the real estate process. Your loan officer must be willing to work and communicate with all of them to keep your deal moving smoothly. 
  They must be skilled and resourceful. It goes without saying that you should only trust true experts to help you navigate the financial side of a real estate deal. 


If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me or my team a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/How+to+Choose+a+Loan+Officer+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/How+to+Choose+a+Loan+Officer+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The loan officer you work with to help facilitate your real estate deal will play a major role in your success, so who should you work with? We’ll discuss this question today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The loan officer you work with to help facilitate your real estate deal will play a major role in your success, so who should you work with? We’ll discuss this question today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Prepare an Offer in a Competitive Real Estate Environment</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-prepare-an-offer-in-a-competitive-real-estate-environment.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-28 23:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+to+Prepare+an+Offer+in+a+Competitive+Real+Estate+Environment+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re out shopping for homes, find the one you love, and are ready to make an offer on it, what do you do next? To answer that question, I’ll tell you how I work with my buyer clients when making an offer in a competitive environment. 

First, I sit down with them and have a detailed conversation about the pros and cons of the property to ensure that it meets all the needs that we discussed in their initial buyer consultation. I also encourage them to talk with their family (or anyone who’ll be living in the home with them) and make sure everyone’s in agreement about putting together a winning offer. 

Next, I have a conversation with the listing agent to find out if the seller has any particular needs we can fulfill. 

“We only get one chance at a first impression.”

After that, we examine what the market is doing in relation to the home’s value. By looking at the MLS, we’ll come up with a price that’s based on comparable homes for sale within the same neighborhood. The final price you offer is up to you, but this data will help you make an educated decision. 

Lastly, I prepare the offer itself. We only get one chance at a first impression, so when the listing agent opens your offer, every detail needs to be covered and they shouldn’t have any questions about it. 

If you have any questions about this or any other real estate topic or you’d like to schedule a buyer consultation, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.  
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+to+Prepare+an+Offer+in+a+Competitive+Real+Estate+Environment+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+to+Prepare+an+Offer+in+a+Competitive+Real+Estate+Environment+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to prepare your offer so that it gets accepted in a competitive real estate environment like ours, here’s what you need to do.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to prepare your offer so that it gets accepted in a competitive real estate environment like ours, here’s what you need to do.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Buyers and Sellers: We Want to Serve You</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/buyers-and-sellers-we-want-to-serve-you.html</link>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-14 10:09:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Buyers+and+Sellers-+We+Want+to+Serve+You.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As your trusted Realtor, my goal is simple: I want to be of service to you. 

With all that goes into the real estate process, navigating the market as a buyer or seller can be overwhelming. It’s for this reason, exactly, that I’d like to offer my help. 

In our digital age, there’s a lot of information available to buyers and sellers. The difference between doing your own research and working with someone like me, though, is massive. 

You see, after years of experience in this industry, I’ve got the tools, knowledge, and experience necessary to help you make the most of your real estate experience. After all, having the necessary information isn’t enough to succeed in our market—you’ve also got to know how to use that information to your advantage. 

“My team and I understand that every buyer and seller is unique and that the way we approach each transaction must reflect this.”

My team and I understand that every buyer and seller is unique and that the way we approach each transaction must reflect this. That’s why when we begin working together, we’ll meet with you to discuss your wants and needs so that we can develop a personalized strategy for your success. Without this level of planning, transactions can drag out much longer than necessary—or worse: they could even fall apart entirely.

The bottom line is this: If you’re thinking of making a move, then reach out to me and let me be of service. I would love the opportunity to develop a custom plan for your real estate goals and then help you execute it in a way that maximizes your success and minimizes your stress.  

If you have any other questions or would like more information, please give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Buyers+and+Sellers-+We+Want+to+Serve+You.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Buyers+and+Sellers-+We+Want+to+Serve+You.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re ready to buy or sell, reach out to us today. We want to help you make the most of your real estate experience.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re ready to buy or sell, reach out to us today. We want to help you make the most of your real estate experience.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Inspections Fit Into a Real Estate Transaction?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-inspections-fit-into-a-real-estate-transaction.html</link>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-02 10:49:15 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+Do+Inspections+Fit+Into+a+Real+Estate+Transaction_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Let’s pretend you’re a seller and we’re at your kitchen table discussing your latest offer. The subject of inspections comes up. Depending on where your property is located, each county in the area has its own customary practices for handling them. 

In some counties, it’s customary for the seller to obtain all the inspections prior to putting the home on the market. In other counties, it’s customary for the buyer to obtain the inspections once the property is already under contract and in the escrow period.

Typically, there will be three to four necessary inspections:

1. General home inspection2. Termite inspection3. Roof inspection4. Chimney inspection (if applicable)5. Pool inspection (if applicable)

In the counties where these inspections are obtained prior to placing the home on the market, it provides a lot of good information on the sales price that is set for your home. It gives the buyer the chance to completely understand the true condition of your home prior to placing an offer on it. 

“There’s a lot of information, but it can be easy to navigate with a professional’s help.”

In the counties where the buyer obtains the inspection in the escrow period, new information is revealed after these inspections are obtained and it will probably lead to a second round of negotiations on the sale of your home.

One more inspection that will probably come up is an appraisal. An appraisal is only required if a buyer is using financing to purchase a home. The goal of the appraiser is to make sure that the home meets the minimum value requirement for the type of financing that will be obtained. If the value doesn’t come in, there could be yet another round of negotiations on the home.

There’s a lot of information to know about inspections and appraisals, but it’s all easy information to navigate through if you and I sit down and have a detailed conversation about the best strategy for your situation.

If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don ‘t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I would love to be of service. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+Do+Inspections+Fit+Into+a+Real+Estate+Transaction_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+How+Do+Inspections+Fit+Into+a+Real+Estate+Transaction_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Inspections are handled differently depending on what county you’re located in. Here’s why that matters whether you’re buying or selling.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Inspections are handled differently depending on what county you’re located in. Here’s why that matters whether you’re buying or selling.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Save Time and Money Paying off Your Mortgage</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-save-time-and-money-paying-off-your-mortgage.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-07 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+_+How+to+Save+Time+and+Money+Paying+off+Your+Mortgage.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When is truly the best time to buy a home? To answer this, I’d like you to consider an old Chinese proverb: “The best time to plant a tree was 20 years ago, and the second best time is today.” 

In short, the point is that there’s no time like the present. If you’re thinking of buying a home, then now is the time to join millions of other Americans who have already taken the plunge into the homeownership dream. 

It’s a proven fact that homeowners have an average net worth that’s 44 times the net worth of the average renter. So while acquiring a mortgage may seem intimidating, the debt associated with a home purchase is actually good debt to have. 

Immediately after closing on a home, your finances may indeed be stretched. Once you’re settled in and get accustomed to homeownership, though, you’ll be in a good position to start thinking about how to tackle your mortgage from a long-term perspective. 

As you think about your strategy for paying off this debt, there are a couple of key questions to consider. First, when do you plan to retire? Also, will you pay off other debts before your mortgage? And, finally, will you leverage your position as a homeowner to purchase investment properties? If so, how will you manage those debts.

“Whether you already own a home or are just now considering a home purchase, there’s no time like the present to evaluate your plan for paying off your mortgage.”

No two homeowners have the exact same goals or the exact same circumstances, so your approach to paying off your mortgage should be equally unique. This is precisely why I partner with people like you: It’s my goal to help you pay off your mortgage, perhaps sooner than later, in a way also benefits the other aspirations you may have. 

There are seven general strategies I’ve outlined for paying off a mortgage before its full term—the first of which is a simple, bi-weekly payment plan. Following this plan, homeowners are called to pay one half of their mortgage payment every two weeks. This equates to 26 total payments over the course of one year. You’ll actually end up paying the equivalent of a full extra mortgage payment after a 12-month period—something that will save you tens of thousands of dollars and shave anywhere between six and eight years off the life of your mortgage. 

Another popular strategy is the 15-year mortgage plan. The current average rate for 15-year mortgages is around 3.5%. If you’ve already lived in your home for a number of years, now could be the ideal time to refinance into a 15-year loan. 

Making one extra payment per quarter is also a good strategy for those looking to save time and money in paying off their mortgage. 

If you’d like to learn more about the strategies I’ve covered today, or about the four other strategies I’ve outlined, then please reach out. 

And, as always, if you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+_+How+to+Save+Time+and+Money+Paying+off+Your+Mortgage.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+_+How+to+Save+Time+and+Money+Paying+off+Your+Mortgage.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Whether you already own a home or are just now considering a home purchase, there’s no time like the present to evaluate your plan for paying off your mortgage.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Whether you already own a home or are just now considering a home purchase, there’s no time like the present to evaluate your plan for paying off your mortgage.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Think Like a Buyer and Get Your Home Sold Quickly and for Top Dollar</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/think-like-a-buyer-and-get-your-home-sold-quickly-and-for-top-dollar.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-26 11:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Team+Paul+Lopez-+Think+Like+a+Buyer+and+Get+Your+Home+Sold+Quickly+and+For+Top+Dollar.mp4</guid>
        <description>

When listing your home, the best way to prepare it for the market and make sure it gets sold quickly and for top dollar is to think like a buyer. 

To think like a buyer, you need to know that buyers are primarily concerned with three factors during their home search: price, location, and condition. Although you can’t change your home’s location, you can do something about its price and condition. 

When it comes to pricing your home, remember that you’re in a competitive situation. In other words, price it according to all of the other comparable homes on the market in your area that you’re competing against. If it’s in the $500,000 price range, how does it stack up against all the other homes in that price range with similar features?

As far as condition goes, look at your home from both a structural and cosmetic standpoint. If you plan on selling within the next three to six months, think about your return on investment in terms of which repairs and upgrades to make. I wouldn’t recommend spending tens of thousands of dollars on renovations; it’s better to make the kinds of improvements that will appeal to buyers in the shortest amount of time. 

“Although you can’t change your home’s location, you can do something about its price and condition.”

The best thing you can do to make sure your home is in top condition is to get it professionally cleaned. Buyers want to be able to visualize living in your home, and this allows them to do that. Cleaning your home for the market is a fine art and a developed skill, though, so make sure you hire a professional to do the job.

If you’re worried that your home doesn’t appeal to the buyers in our market, don’t be. That’s where a Realtor such as myself comes into play. I can walk through your home, determine what its key selling points are, and develop a marketing plan to emphasize those points. 

If you’d like to schedule a walk-through appointment for your home or you have any other questions about how to sell it quickly and for top dollar, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Team+Paul+Lopez-+Think+Like+a+Buyer+and+Get+Your+Home+Sold+Quickly+and+For+Top+Dollar.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Team+Paul+Lopez-+Think+Like+a+Buyer+and+Get+Your+Home+Sold+Quickly+and+For+Top+Dollar.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>The key to preparing your home for the market is to think like a buyer. Here’s what I mean by that.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>The key to preparing your home for the market is to think like a buyer. Here’s what I mean by that.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3 Tips That Will Make Your Home Purchase Smooth & Seamless</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/3-tips-that-will-make-your-home-purchase-smooth-seamless.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-12 16:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+2+Tips+That+Will+Make+Your+Home+Purchase+Smooth+%26+Seamless.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Whether you’re a first-time homebuyer or a veteran homebuyer, there are a few tips you need to remember to make your purchase as smooth and seamless as possible from a financial perspective. 

First, consider your closing costs. If you’re a first-time homebuyer, you can get a mortgage loan that requires a down payment of as little as 3%, but you can’t forget about your closing costs. 

As a rule of thumb, closing costs generally make up 3% to 5% of the price of the home. If your home costs $350,000, for instance, you should expect to pay at least $12,000 in closing costs. Since that’s roughly the same amount as your down payment, you’d have to bring $24,000 in total to close on the home. 

“You can’t forget about your closing costs.”

If you enter into a purchase agreement and you don’t have the necessary funds set aside for the closing costs, you’ll find yourself at a competitive disadvantage because you’ll have to ask for concessions from the seller. 

Second, make sure you know the home’s true condition. The seller is required to disclose everything they know about the home, but oftentimes, they won’t know about any current defects, so finding out if there are any falls squarely on you. 

To do this, you’ll need to order some inspections. For all of my clients, I recommend they order a home inspection, pest inspection, roof report, and—depending on the home’s amenities—a chimney or pool inspection. All of these will cost between $800 and $1,000, but the information you gain from them is well worth it. 

Finally, figure out how much cash you’ll need to close. Along with the home inspection we mentioned earlier, there are a number of additional expenses homebuyers must expect as they prepare to seal the deal. These expenses will vary slightly, but, in general, will run you between 2% and 5% of the purchase price.

If you’d like to know more about how to prepare for your home purchase, give me a call and I’d be happy to schedule a free consultation that will guide you through the process step by step. 

If you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+2+Tips+That+Will+Make+Your+Home+Purchase+Smooth+%26+Seamless.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+2+Tips+That+Will+Make+Your+Home+Purchase+Smooth+%26+Seamless.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Are you preparing to buy a home? Here are a few tips that will help you from a financial perspective.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Are you preparing to buy a home? Here are a few tips that will help you from a financial perspective.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Mistakes to Steer Clear From if You’re Looking to Rent</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/mistakes-to-steer-clear-from-if-youre-looking-to-rent.html</link>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-21 12:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Mistakes+to+Steer+Clear+From+If+Youre+Looking+to+Rent.mp4</guid>
        <description>

18 years ago, I got my start in real estate as a mortgage loan officer. After later transitioning into a job as an agent, I finally landed in my current role: property management. I take a lot of pride and joy in helping countless families rent homes as an alternative to purchasing a home.

Today I’m going to delve further into my philosophy on renting, so follow along in the video above to learn more.

Cited below for your convenience are timestamps that will direct you to various points in the video. Feel free to watch the full message or use these timestamps to browse specific topics at your leisure: 

0:48 - My philosophy on renting

1:26 - The three factors that make it difficult for people to rent

1:57 - Reason No. 1 - Your credit profile

4:34 - Reason No. 2 - Documentation

5:42 - Reason No. 3 - Paying in cash

7:22 - A recap of today’s topic and how to get in touch with me

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Mistakes+to+Steer+Clear+From+If+Youre+Looking+to+Rent.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Paul+Lopez/Paul+Lopez+Real+Estate+_+Mistakes+to+Steer+Clear+From+If+Youre+Looking+to+Rent.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you want to rent a property, there are three major roadblocks that may prevent you from doing so.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you want to rent a property, there are three major roadblocks that may prevent you from doing so.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Answering the 3 Most Common Questions I Hear From Clients</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/answering-the-3-most-common-questions-i-hear-from-clients.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-07 13:32:01 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Over the last 18 years, I’ve answered countless questions from homebuyers and sellers about the real estate market and about real estate in general. I recently sat down to answer three of the most common questions I’m asked on a daily basis and share my expert opinion on each of them. Here’s an outline of the questions I answered in this video, with timestamps so that you can skip ahead to the question(s) that interest you most:

0:50- Is it a good time to buy a home right now?4:32- Is it a good time to sell a home right now?7:08- What geographical areas do my team and I cover in California?

I hope you found the answers to these common questions helpful. No matter what your situation is, I’m always happy to help you achieve your real estate goals. If you have any additional questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’m answering the three most common questions I hear from clients on a daily basis.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’m answering the three most common questions I hear from clients on a daily basis.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To My Blog!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Paul Lopez</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-09 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Our market remains busy, and it’s still an opportune time to command a high price selling your home.  

I know what’s happening in the San Joaquin and Alameda County areas, specifically pertaining to home values, that will directly affect you.

So, I’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated.

They will be valuable and useful in helping you stay on top of what’s happening in the community.

Check back because content will be coming soon!

I’m excited to keep you updated on what’s happening in the San Joaquin and Alameda County areas!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My monthly messages will provide you with market updates, tips, and other educational information having to do with our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Paul Lopez</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My monthly messages will provide you with market updates, tips, and other educational information having to do with our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Tracy, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Paul Lopez</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Paul Lopez</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Team Paul Lopez - your professional Tracy Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
